This translation is only for the remastered version of Game of Thrones
http://kat.cr/game-of-thrones-seasons-1-5-censored-t12644205.html
Uploaded by : Nymeria95
-= www.OpenSubtitles.org =-
Game of Thrones
Season One - Episode Four
Episode title : Cripples, Bastards, Broken Things
Translation
Dr. Samer_Salama
dr_samer_salama@hotmail.com
The young lord is having dreams
again
We have visitors -
I don't want to meet anyone.
Really?
If you're cooped up all day.
and no one to entertain me but this old bat.
I'm going crazy
After all, you don't have a choice.
Rob is waiting.)
I don't want to go.
neither do I -
(But Robb, the leader of Winterfell
which means I'm doing his bidding.
and you're doing mine.
(Hodor)!
Hodor )? -
Help Bran get to the auditorium.
(Hodor)
I have to admit that the welcome
was much warmer on my previous visit.
Anyone from the Night's Watch is welcome
(at Winterfell
(Anyone from the Night's Watch.
But not me, huh, kid?
(I'm not your boy, Lannister.
I am the leader of Winterfell in my father's absence
Then you must learn the courtesy of leaders.
So it's true
(Hello Bran
Do you remember anything about what happened?
He has no memory of that day
Strange -
Why are you here?
Is it possible for your fellow wizard to kneel?
My neck is starting to hurt.
(Kneel down, Hodor.
Do you like to ride, Bran?
Yes - -
I mean ..... I used to love him
The kid lost the use of his legs.
So what?
With the right saddle and horse
even a cripple can ride
I'm not disabled.
So I'm not a dwarf.
My father will be happy to hear that.
I have a gift for you
Give this to the saddle maker.
He will complete the rest.
You must adjust the horse to fit the rider
They put him on a horse
and teach him to respond.
With the bridle and the boy's voice
Will I be able to ride again?
will do
on horseback.
You'll be as tall as their tallest man.
Is this a trick?
You didn't help him?
I'm a sensitive person in front of
Handicapped, foundlings, and other broken things.
Well done to my brother
Winterfell is honored to host you.)
Spare me your false compliments.
(Lord Stark.
There's a fun house outside your walls.
I'll find the bed there.
And we'll both sleep better.
If you like redheads
(ask for Rose
Come to say goodbye, Greyjoy?
You're so kind.
(Your boss doesn't seem to like Lannisters.
He's not my boss.
No, of course.
What happened here?
Where's Mrs. Stark?
Why didn't you meet me?
She's a little indisposed.
She's not in Winterfell, is she?
Where did she go?
My lady's place -
Ma'am?
Your loyalty to your captors is touching.
Tell me, how would it feel
(Belen Greyjoy)
if he saw his only surviving son
turned into a humble servant?
I still remember watching my father's fleet
(Burning in Lanesport
I guess your uncle was responsible for that?
It must have been quite a sight.
There's nothing more beautiful than watching sailors
burned alive.
Yes, a great victory for your people.
But alas, the ending was an embarrassing one.
We were outnumbered.
A foolish revolution, then.
I think your father knew that.
When your brother died in battle
And now here you are, the servant of your enemies.
Look out, goblin!
I pissed you off.
Forgive me, it's been a long morning.
Anyway, don't get discouraged.
I'm a big disappointment for my father
I've learned to live with it.
Your next fling with Rose is on me.
I'll try not to wear her out.
Legs, shoulders, legs.
Left leg forward
good
Now turn while the strike is executed.
Use all your weight
What is it?
This thing's gonna need more than a hell of a lot more.
Tell them your name
(Samuel Tarly)
(From Horn Hill
(I mean, I was from Horn Hill.
I've come to wear black.
You mean black candy.
Well, it can't be
worse than it looks.
... (Rust)
Show us what he can do
I surrender
Please, enough.
on your feet -
Pick up your sword.
Hit him until he finds his feet
Looks like the butchers and thieves have run out in the south.
Now they're sending us some weak pigs.
(John)!
Again, stronger.
I give up! I surrender
! Enough
He gave up
The bastard seems to have fallen in love
All right, then.
(Lord Snow
You want to defend your crush.
Let's make it a practice run.
The two of you are enough.
to make this pig squeal.
All you have to do
is bypass the bastard.
Do you really want to do this?
no -
I surrender, I surrender, I surrender.
surrender
Enough for today
Go and clean the armor.
That's all you're good for.
Well done on the fight
Did they hurt you?
I've been through worse
(You can call me Sam
if you want to
(My mom calls me Sam.
Things aren't going to get any easier, you know?
You have to stand up for yourself.
Why didn't you stand up and fight?
I wanted to
But I couldn't.
Why not?
I'm a coward
My father always says that.
The wall is no place for cowards.) -
I know
I'm sorry
I just wanted to... Thank you
Fucking coward
They saw us talking to him.
Now they'll think we're cowards too.
You're too stupid to be a coward.
..... And you're too stupid to be.
Come on, hurry up.
Before the summer is over
Come on
(Vice Dothraki)
City of warriors
Pile of mud
This is the best that savages can do.
These are my people now.
You shouldn't call them savages.
I'll call them whatever I want
because they are my people
This is my army
Kal Drogo is heading in the wrong direction with my army.)
(If my brother is given an army of Dothraki
Can he conquer the
the Seven Kingdoms?)
Dothraki ) did not cross )
narrow sea ) before )
They fear any water that their
for their horses to drink
But if they do?
King Robert is foolish enough
enough to fight them over a large area.
But his advisors are different
And you know them?
I fought alongside them once.
A long time ago
And now Ned Stark wants my head.
He kicked me off my land
I traded slaves
Yes
Why?
I didn't have the money.
And my wife was demanding.
And where is she now?
Elsewhere
with another man
Someday, your husband will sit here.
And you're going to sit next to him.
And one day, not too far away.
you will present your child to the court.
(All Lords of Westeros
They will gather here to see the little prince
What if I have a girl?
Oh, come on, you're gonna have
boys and girls and lots of them.
What if I only give birth to girls?
I wouldn't worry about it
Jenny Bowles' mom had five children
all girls
Yes, but it's out of the question.
But so what?
Well, if you only have girls.
I believe the throne will pass
(to Prince Joffrey's younger brother
and everyone will hate me.
No one can hate you
Joffrey (hates me) -
nonsense -
Why do you say that?
It's all because of wolves?
(Sansa)
I told you a hundred times
..... Wolves are not -
please shut up -
Do you remember your lessons?
Who built the Iron Throne?
Aegon ) occupied )
And who built the Red Cape?
Major ) Cruel )
... And how many years did it take to build
My grandfather and uncle were killed here once upon a time.
They were killed on the orders of
King Ares, yes.
(The Mad King
(Publicly known as the Mad King.
Why were they killed?
You should talk to your dad.
about these things.
I don't ever want to talk to my dad.
Sansa (in the depths of your heart)
You will forgive your father
No, I won't.
It's the King's Helper tournament that causes
All this mess, sir.
! Starring the King's Aide.
I assure you, the assistant doesn't even want it.
(Call it what you will, Lord Stark.
The city is packed with people
and they're still coming in every day.
Last night there was a bar riot
A fire in a fun house
Three stabbings and a drunken race
(with horses on the streets of Sisters.
Terrible -
If you can't keep the king's peace.
it seems that the command of the guard should be
under someone else's command
I need more men.
You'll get fifty.
Lord Baelish. You will pay -
I will.
You'll find money not for tournament prizes
You'll find the money
for peacekeeping
and I'll give you 20 men from my personal guard.
Until the crowds leave
Thank you, Mr. Assistant
I will use them well.
The sooner we get this over with.
the better.
The Kingdom thrives on such occasions.
such events, sir.
provides many with a chance for glory.
And for the simple people, a chance to forget their misfortunes.
All the hostels are full in the city
I'm sure the tournament will line the pockets of many
.... Now -
if nothing else.
Gentlemen?
Oh, my God, this heat.
On days like this, I envy you northerners.
You and your summer snow
Until tomorrow, sir.
I was hoping to talk to you
(About John Arin
Lord Arin?
His death was
It's sad for us
I personally took care of him, but
But I couldn't save him.
He got sick
Hard and fast
I met him in my room
The night before he died
Lord John often
come to me for counseling
Why?
I was the senior counselor for many years
Kings and lieutenants
..... my advice since
What did John want the night before he died?
He came to me looking for a book
Book?
What book?
Uh... I'm afraid
He won't be of any interest to you, sir.
Huge folder
No, I want to read it.
Genealogy & History
(The Great Families of the Seven Kingdoms
with descriptions of some of the noblemen
and the nobles and their children
Harkon Amber ) the first to bear this name)
(Born to Lord Heather Amber
(and Mrs. Amaryllis Amber
In the year one hundred and eighty-three
(After the arrival of Aegon
(To Last Hearth
Blue eyes, brown hair
and light-skinned
He died at the age of fourteen
Due to wounds sustained while hunting a bear
As I told you, sir.
A lot of reading
Did Arin tell you what he wanted from him?
He didn't, sir.
And I didn't ask him.
(John's death.
great tragedy -
Did he say anything to you in his final hours?
Nothing important, sir.
Actually .... There is a phrase
He kept repeating it
"The breed is strong."
I think.
"The breed is strong"? -
And what does that mean?
The dying mind
(Lord Stark's confused mind
Even though it's very important
However, the final words
Like the first words
And you're sure his death was natural?
What else could it be?
poison
Confusing idea
No, no, no, I don't think so.
The assistant was well-liked by everyone
.... What kind of man would dare
I've heard that poison is
women's weapon
Yes, women
.... Servants
and eunuchs
Did you know that Lord Varys is a eunuch?
Everyone knows that
Uh, yeah, yeah. of course
How did someone like him end up
In the King's Counselors
I will never know.
You've wasted a lot of your time.
No problem, my lord.
It's a great honor.
Uh, thank you.
I'll go out myself
Siriu (says the water dancers)
They can stand on one finger
one finger for hours
The distance is high in these grades
Siriu says that every damage is a lesson.)
And every lesson makes you better.
Tomorrow, I'll start chasing cats.
Cats?
Siriu ( says )
He says that swordsmen should
should study cats
It's as quiet as the shadows
And light as feathers
You have to be fast to catch them.
He's right about that.
Now that Bran is awake.
Is he coming to live with us?
Well, he has to recover first.
He wants to be one of the Knights of the King's Guard.
He can't do that now, can he?
No.
But one day
(Lord Holdfast may become
or one of the king's advisors
Or he may build castles
(like the builder Brandon
Can I be a Mrs.
Hold Fast?)
You will marry a gentleman.
and you will rule his castle.
And your sons will be knights.
princes and lords
No
That's not me
Hey there.
Sir Alistair says that I'm
I'll be your new partner in the guard.
But I must warn you.
I don't see very well
Come and approach the fire
Warmer.
No, it's okay, I'm fine.
I'm not
You are freezing
I don't like high places
Can't fight
Can't see
She's afraid of heights and everything.
everything else, apparently.
What are you doing here, Sam?
My father on the morning of my eighteenth birthday
came to me
"You're almost a man now."
He said that
But you don't deserve my titles and possessions.
(Tomorrow, you're going to join the Guardians.
Forget claiming all your inheritance.
and reinvent yourself in the North.
"If you don't
he said to me
"So, we're going on a fishing trip.
And somewhere in those woods.
your horse will stumble
And you will fall and you will die.
Or that's what I'm going to tell your mom.
Nothing would make me happier
Sir Alistair will make me fight again.
again tomorrow, won't he?
Yes, he will
You know, I'm not getting any better.
.... Okay.
And it's not going to get any worse.
I hear you're reading a boring book.
Bissell (talking a lot)
It never stops
Do you know Sir Hugh from the valley?
I'm not surprised
Until recently
He was just a companion
(John Arin's companion)
He was promoted to Knight directly
After the death of his master
Knight for what?
Why are you telling me this?
I promised Kat that I would help you.
Where is Sir Hugh?
I'll talk to him -
Very bad idea.
See that kid over there?
One of the little Faris birds
spider ) Very interested in your movements )
(Spider is a nickname for Pharis)
Now look over there.
This is one of the Queen's spies.
And you see the maid who pretends
reading a book?
Varis or the Queen?)
No, she's one of my spies.
Is there someone at your service
that you trust implicitly?
Yes -
The wise answer was no, sir.
Send a message to your ideal server
And discreetly, he sent him to investigate.
(with Sir Hugh
Next, you might want him to visit
a certain blacksmith
He lives in a huge house on Al-Hadid Street
Why?
As I told you, I also have spies.
(And they seem to have seen Lord Arryn.
He visits this blacksmith more than once
in his last week
Lord Baelish, it seems I was wrong
about my suspicions about you.
Not trusting me was the wisest thing to do
I've done since you got off your horse.
..... Two, three
Twenty-four, five.
Six, twenty-seven.
Twenty-eight, twenty-nine.
Sir Hugh?
Thirty, thirty-one, thirty-two.
Sir Hugh!
As you can see, I'm busy.
I'm here on behalf of Lord
(Eddard Stark.)
King's assistant
I'm his guard captain.
Sorry, I didn't catch your name.
Sir ....?
"No siree.
I'm not a knight
So, I happen to be me.
He said he would be happy to speak with the assistant in person
He's a knight, you see.
Knight
They strut around here like roosters
Even the ones who didn't see
any arrows coming their way.
You're not supposed to be out here, sir.
We don't know who's watching us.
Let them watch -
The ex-assistant did talk to me
more than once
But unfortunately, I didn't have the honor of working for him.
What did Lord Arin want?
He always came for the kid.
I want to see him, too.
As you wish, sir.
(Jandre)!
Here it is.
Strong for his age
works hard
Let the assistant see the hat
you made, boy.
It's a work of art.
not for sale -
Boy, he's the king's assistant.
.... If he wants the hat -
I made it for myself -
Forgive me, sir.
There's nothing to forgive.
When Lord Arin came to visit you.
what were you talking about?
Just a few questions, sir.
What kind of question?
First, about my work.
If I'm treated well
If I like the place
But then he started asking me about my mom
Your mom?
Who was she and what did she look like?
And what did you tell him?
She died when I was young
She had yellow hair
And she used to sing to me sometimes.
Look at me
Get back to work, kid.
If the day comes when a boy decides
Using guns instead of making them
Send it to me
Did you find anything?
(King Robert's bastard)
This is for the King
(From Lord Stark.
..... Should I leave it with
Listen
Do you hear them?
How much do you think he has in there?
Guess -
Three?
four
He likes to do it when
I'm on guard duty
He makes me listen while he insults my sister.
Forgive me, sir.
Why should I forgive you?
Have you wronged me?
You know, we've met before.
Uh-huh. Really?
Funny, I don't remember.
(Pike's Blockade)
We fought side by side one evening
And that's where you got your internship?
Yes - -
A Greyjoy almost took my eye.
They're brutal bastards.
They love bloodshed.
But in the end, stop it.
It was a decisive battle
(I remember Thors of Meyer City
as he broke through their ranks
With his flaming sword?
I'll remember it as long as I live.
(I saw the youngest of the Greyjoy boys
(in Winterfell
It was like watching a shark
on top of a mountain
Theon?)
He's a good kid.
I doubt it
I bet you smell
I bet you smell Like cranberry jam.
Come on
Can I leave this with you?
A letter from Lord Stark?
(I do not serve Lord Stark.
Where have you been?
surveillance -
( with ( Sam -
Prince Chopped Pork -
Where is he?
He's not hungry.
No way! Impossible
That's enough
Sam is no different than the rest of us here.)
He had no place in this world.
That's why he came here.
We won't hurt him on the practice field anymore.
(We won't, no matter what Thorne says.
He's our brother now.
And we will protect him.
You're already in love
(Lord Snow
You're the girls, do what you want.
But if Thorne puts me up against that pig
I'll cut myself some bacon from it.
(No one touches Sam
What are you waiting for?
Attack him!
You come here.
Hit me
Come on, hit me.
I give up! I surrender
I give up. I give up.
I surrender
You think that's funny, huh?
When you're out there
(Behind the wall
And when the sun goes down
Do you want a man to protect you?
Or a crybaby?
You sent that bitch to order me around?
I was supposed to
I was supposed to! I'm sending you her head.
Forgive me, my queen.
I did as you said
It's okay now.
Ari) Take it and leave) -
Okay, my queen.
Why did you hit her?
How many times do I have to tell you?
You're not ordering me around.
I wasn't ordering you
I just wanted to invite you over for dinner.
What is this?
It's a gift.
I made it especially for you.
(Dothraki Rags
You're going to dress me now?
Please.
It's all dung
all
Stop... stop
You want to turn me into one, don't you?
Next will be braiding my hair
You are not allowed to braid
You haven't won a fight yet.
Don't talk to me like that! Don't talk to me like that.
You're just a whore to their leader.
..... And now, you've awakened the dragon.
I am a Dothraki queen!
I am the wife of the Great Kaal
and I'm carrying his son in my belly.
The next time you raise your hand to me
will be the last time
time you have two hands
I know that some of the leaders here
(sneaking into the pleasure house in the city of Moult
I don't doubt it
Don't you think that's not fair?
They make us swear an oath
while they sneak around
Pleasure houses?
It's ridiculous, isn't it?
(What, we can't protect the wall
unless we're single
It's ridiculous
I didn't think it would bother you so much.
And why not?
Because I'm fat?
No.
But I like girls just like you.
They may not like me, of course
I've never been with one before
You must have done it a thousand times.
No
In fact
I'm just like you.
Yes
I find that hard to believe
I almost did it once.
I was alone in a room
... with a naked girl, but
..... Was it
Old and ugly?
Young and charming
(A prostitute named Rose
What color is her hair?
Red -
I love red hair.
...... and
You don't want to know.
That good?
Even better -
So why exactly
You didn't have sex with Rose, the owner of the .....?
What is my name?
( John Snow )
And why is my nickname Snow?
...... because you
You are a bastard
from the north
I haven't met my mom.
My father didn't even tell me her name.
I don't know if she's alive or dead.
I don't know if she's a noble.
.... or a hunter's wife
or a prostitute
So I stood there
In the pleasure house
While Rose was undressing
But I couldn't do it
Because all I was thinking about
What if I get her pregnant?
And she had a baby.
Another bastard named Snow?
It's not a good life for a child
... So
Did not know?
Do you enjoy each other?
Feeling cold, boys?
The cold is a bit pungent
A little pungent.
Yeah, near the fire.
Inside housing
And it's still summer
Do you even remember the last winter?
How long has it been?
Ten years?
I remember
Was it cozy at Winterfell?
Were there days when
when you couldn't keep warm no matter what you did?
No matter how many fires your
set by your servants?
I was lighting my own fire.
how impressive -
I spent six months abroad there
(behind) the wall
Last winter
It was supposed to be a mission
for two weeks
(We heard a rumor that Mance Rayder's men
were planning an attack on the East Tower.
So we went out looking for some of his men
Let's catch them and gather some information.
(Barbarians fighting with Mance
Tough guys
Tougher than you by a long shot.
They know these places better than we do
They knew a storm was coming.
So they hid in their caves
and waited for the storm to pass.
We got caught in the storm.
Strong winds
to the point of uprooting a hundred-foot-tall tree out of the ground.
with roots and everything.
And it's all in the dark
You don't know cold
Neither do you.
The horses died first
We didn't have enough food to feed her.
to keep her warm
Eating horses was easy
.... But when we started to fall
That wasn't easy
We were supposed to have boys like you.
weren't we?
Fat and soft like you
We could have lived on you for two weeks.
and your bones would have been left for soup.
Soon we will receive new recruits
And you will be under the command of the lord in charge.
For missions
And they will call you
(night watchmen
But you'd be a fool to believe that.
You're still young.
.... And when winter comes, you will die.
Like flies
I hit him
I hit the dragon
Your brother Rhaegar was the last dragon
Viserys (Less Than)
shadow of a snake
But he is the heir to the throne.
In fact
Do you want to see your brother sitting
on the Iron Throne?
No
But the general public is waiting for it
Illyrio ) He said they are sewing dragon banners)
and praying for his return.
The common people are praying for rain, health
and an endless summer
They don't care what the nobles do
What are you praying for, Sir Jorah?
Sir Jorah?
Home
I'm praying for the house, too.
(My brother will not be able to reclaim the Seven Kingdoms.
He won't be able to lead an army.
even if my husband gave him an army.
He won't bring us home.
Lovers quarreling?
I'm sorry.
... Is it?
(Dear Sansa, it's Lord Baelish
.... He is known as
An old family friend
I've known your mom for a long time.
Why do they call you Littlefinger?
Aria!
Don't be rude.
No, it's okay.
When I was a kid
I was small
And I come from a small town
(called Fingers.
So as you can see
It's a very clever nickname
I've been waiting here for days.
Start the fucking duel!
Who is this?
(Sir Gregor Klagen
(They call it The Mountain
(The Hound's older brother
And his opponent?
Sir Hugh from the valley.
(John Arin's companion was
Look what he's become.
Yeah, now fight.
Not what you were expecting?
Didn't anyone ever tell you
the story of The Mountain and The Hound?
A beautiful story of brotherly love
The Hound was just a kid.)
Six years old, maybe.
Gregor ) He was a few years older)
He was a young lad.
and he had gained some notoriety.
Some lucky kids
Born with a talent for violence
One day, Gregor found his
his little brother
Playing a game near the fire.
(Game (Gregor)
Wooden knight
Gregor didn't say a word.)
He just grabbed his brother
by the back of his neck
and put his face on the burning coals.
Hold it like this
While the boy was screaming
while his face was melting
Many people don't know this story
I won't tell anyone.
I promise
No, please don't.
If The Hound hears you tell it
(I'm afraid all the knights in King's Landing
They can't save you.
My lord.
Her Majesty, the Queen.
Your Majesty -
Your Majesty! Your heroism misses you -
Putting my name on it
doesn't mean it's my tournament
I think it's best if we forget
what happened between us on Kings Road.
Problem wolves
Forcing you to kill the monster
was extreme.
Even though we sometimes go to extremes
in order to protect our children.
How (Sansa)?
She likes it here.
It's the only Stark that does that.
Like her mother
Not too northern
What are you doing here?
I'm going to ask you the same question.
What do you want to accomplish?
The King asked me to serve him
and to serve the kingdom.
And that's what I'm going to do until
until he tells me otherwise.
You can't change him
You can't help him
He'll do what he wants, as he always has.
and you'll do your best to minimize the damage.
If this is my mission
so be it
You're just a soldier.
Isn't it?
Take your orders and move on.
I guess it makes sense.
Your older brother was trained to lead.
and you were trained to follow.
I was also trained to kill my enemies.
Your Majesty.
Me, too.
God bless you
Good company.
And so do you.
Oh, boy! Hey, kid.
Bread, meat, beer... quickly
Excellent idea, Grandpa.
I'm starving.
.... A song while we wait?
I'd rather throw myself into a well
Come on, Grandpa, this could be
this could be your last chance since you're heading north.
The only music he knows
Northerners know is the howling of wolves.
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry, sir.
The place is full.
All places -
My men can stay in the stable
For me, I don't need a big place.
Really, sir, there's nowhere.
..... Isn't there anything I can do
To get rid of this?
You can take my place
Now that's a smart man.
You can provide food, I guess?
Yorn ) Come with me )
Yes, sir.
(Lord Lannister.
Can I entertain you while you eat?
I can sing about
(your father's victory at King's Landing.
Nothing would ruin my dinner like that.
Ms. Stark!
What a happy coincidence
I was sorry I didn't meet you
(at Winterfell
Ms. Stark!
(I was still Caitlin Tully
The last time I came here
Hey, mister.
Is that a black harlequin bat
on your coat?
It is, ma'am.
(And is Mrs. Wint
a true and loyal friend
(To my father, Lord Hoster Tully.
From River Run?
It is so
The Red Stallion was always)
(welcomed at River Run
My father considers
(Jonas Bracken)
One of his oldest and most loyal allies
Our leader is honored by this trust
I envy your father.
and all his friends
(Ms. Stark
But I really don't get it.
What's the point of this?
I know your motto too.
(Twin Towers in Frye
How's your boss doing, mister?
Lord Wilder is well, ma'am.
He asked your father to honor his presence.
On his 90th birthday
Planning to take another wife.
This guy
He came to my house as a guest
and there's a conspiracy to kill my son.
Ten year old child
(in the name of King Robert
and the leaders you serve
I ask you to arrest him.
and help me get him back.
(to Winterfell
To receive the king's justice
With my compliments
Dr. Samer Salama
-= www.OpenSubtitles.org =-